refinery29.com 2015-12-25

# R29's Privacy Policy - Your Information Is Protected on Refinery29

Last updated: May 13, 2015

Refinery 29 Inc. (“Refinery29” or “we”) takes your privacy extremely seriously. This privacy policy describes how we treat and use the information we collect when you visit or use our web site Refinery29.com, mobile-optimized versions of the web site, or software applications to which this policy is linked (collectively, “Website”), including when you sign-up for our newsletters.  
Your use of our Website will indicate your understanding and agreement to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, disclosures and other uses of your information as described in this privacy policy.

### Collection of Information

**Children.** We do not offer the Website to anyone under the age 18 and do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. No one under age 13 may provide any information to or on the Website. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any personal information on or through the Website, register on the Website, or use any of the interactive or public comment features of this Website or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, email address or any screen name or user name you may use.

**Information You Provide.** We generally collect personally identifiable information that you voluntarily provide. For instance, information may be collected when you: sign up for our newsletters, create an account/register on our Website, complete a survey, post a comment to an article on our Website, enter a sweepstakes or contest, or participate in our social networking features. Further, you may be asked to provide your email address, your name, buying preferences, annual income, or other demographic or profile information, Twitter or Facebook usernames or other usernames and aliases used for purposes of linking to and/or posting on your social media accounts, and other information you choose to submit. We will collect such information as well as any other content that you provide to us in engaging in any of the above activities or any other activities on the Website. Additionally, if you elect to post material to any blogs, forums, or participate in our community boards that may be offered on our Website, then such materials will be collected and may be publicly available for others to view. Even after you terminate your account, all such materials submitted by you on the Website or our social media channels may be retained by us indefinitely and we may continue to disclose such materials publicly.

**Other Information We Collect.** We and other parties may also collect information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or other online services (behavioral tracking), such as pages visited and how often and for how long they are visited. We may use various technologies and features to collect this information, such as tracking your activities through your Internet Protocol (IP) address, computer settings or most-recently visited URL, as well as through the use of “cookies” and “web beacons” described below.

**Do-Not-Track Signals.** Because there is not yet a consensus on how companies should respond to web browser-based or other “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) mechanisms, we currently do not respond to web browser DNT signals that provide a method to opt out of the collection of information about online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services. We may revisit our policy on responding to these signals, in which case we will post a revised privacy policy on this site. See “Modifications” below.

**Cookies.** We may place and access cookies and similar technologies on your computer, tablet or mobile device. A cookie is a small amount of data (often including a unique identifier), that is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies may help you navigate the Website. We may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to prevent you from having to reenter your username and password each time you access the Website. We may also use cookies to control the display of ads, to track usage patterns on the sites, to deliver editorial content, to record requests for subscriptions, to personalize information and to collect aggregate Website usage information, as described below. You can delete these cookies by changing your privacy preferences in your Internet browser. You also have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of the Website that depend on cookies. Some of our third party partners (including advertisers and marketing services companies) may set and access cookies and similar technologies on your computer as well, or we may do so on their behalf. We do not have control over how these third parties use such cookies and similar technologies or the information derived therefrom.

**Web Beacons.** We may also use “web beacons” (also known as “clear GIFs” or “pixel tags”) or similar technologies, on the Website and in our communications with you to enable us to know whether you have visited a web page or received a message. A web beacon is typically a one-pixel, transparent image (although it can be a visible image as well), located on a web page or in an e-mail or other type of message, which is retrieved from a remote site on the Internet enabling the verification of an individual's viewing or receipt of a web page or message. A web beacon may enable us to relate your viewing or receipt of a web page or message to other information about you, including your personally identifiable information.

**Location Information.** We may, and may enable our advertisers to, collect your location via certain services we provide through digital applications, wireless access protocol services ("WAP Services") or mobile phone services. We, or the service provider, will inform you of such collection at the time you use the service. By using such service, you hereby consent to our collection, use and disclosure of your location information as described.

**General Usage Information.** In addition, we may gather aggregate usage information about Website users on an anonymous basis. This information is not personally identifiable and will be used to determine how our Website is being used. Examples of such information include: How much time do users spend on our site? What pages do they view? What sites did they come from? What sites do they go to? All of this information is collected to help us create a better, faster, more efficient website and to provide you with better content. We may also share aggregate usage information, in aggregate anonymous form, with our prospective and actual business partners, advertisers and other third parties for any business purpose.

### Use of Information

We typically use your information:

  * to provide you with newsletters and additional information regarding products and services from Refinery29 or from others that may be of interest to you;
  * to fulfill any other purpose for which you provide the information; for example, if you enter our on-line sweepstakes, we may use your email to notify that you won;
  * to notify you, at our discretion, about changes to our Website or any products or services we offer or provide though it;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features on our Website;
  * to gain insights that help us to make improvements to the design and performance of the Website; 
  * in any other way we may describe when you provide the information; and
  * for any other purpose with your consent.

We may disclose your information, including content or other data posted, uploaded or provided by you, if, among other things, we are required to do so by law or in the following situations and for the following purposes: 

  * to comply with legal process; 
  * to enforce the Terms of Use; 
  * to respond to claims that any content violates the rights of third parties; 
  * to respond to your requests for customer service; 
  * to protect our rights, property or personal safety, or the rights, property or personal safety of our users or the public; 
  * if the entity to which your information is disclosed is a third party who wants to promote goods and services that we believe would be of interest to you;
  * if the entity to which your information is disclosed is our subsidiary, affiliate or parent company;
  * if we choose to sell your information to selected third parties, and such third parties will not be required to comply with this privacy policy;
  * if we partner with a retailer or other third party to offer online shopping opportunities, contest or sweepstakes, services, subscriptions and other applications, then (i) personally identifiable information you provide in connection with the above transactions may be collected directly by, or shared by us with, the third party, and (ii) these third parties will use your information in accordance with their own privacy policy;
  * when we utilize third party service providers to provide products, services or functions on our behalf (such as sending emails or fulfilling subscriptions), these service providers may use your information to carry out the purpose(s) for which we hired them, but not for any other purposes;
  * otherwise with your consent or in accordance with your indicated preferences (e.g., you indicated you wanted to receive promotional materials directly from a third party partner); or
  * in connection with a sale, merger, transfer, exchange, or other disposition (whether of assets, stock, or otherwise) of all or a portion of the business conducted by the Website to which this policy applies, in which case the acquiring company will possess the information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personally identifiable information as described in this privacy policy.

### Social Networks

If you use your login credentials from a social networking site (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Pinterest) ("SNS") on our Website, we may receive information from such SNS in accordance with the terms and conditions (e.g., terms of use and privacy policy) of the SNS ("SNS Terms"). If you elect to share your information with these SNS, we will share information with them in accordance with your election. The SNS Terms of these SNS will apply to the information we disclose to them. Additionally, if you make an election with respect to a SNS while on our Website (for instance, if you elect to “follow” us on one of the SNS, or “Like” us on Facebook), your election will be reflected and may be shared with your social network within the applicable SNS. We reserve the right to use and disclose all personally identifiable information and other information about you that we receive through SNS in the same ways described in this privacy policy.

### Your California Privacy Rights: Notice to California Customers

California's "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about the businesses’ practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties during the preceding year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes or give to the customers an option to opt-out of such information-sharing. To make such request, send us an email at [privacy@refinery29.com](mailto:privacy@refinery29.com) or write us at Refinery 29 Inc. 225 Broadway, 23rd Floor, New York, NY 10007, indicating “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject of your email or letter, your name and complete mailing address. We are not responsible for requests that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year.

### Review and Access

Upon request, Refinery29 will provide you with a summary of the information we have collected about you, and the opportunity to correct, update or modify this information.

### How to Opt Out

You can unsubscribe from receiving Refinery29 newsletters or commercial emails at any time. You can unsubscribe by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link in the footer of any Refinery29 email and following the instructions, or by logging into your account on our Website, selecting “Subscriptions” and clicking “Unsubscribe” button on “My Newsletters” menu. But note that you may continue to receive certain communications from us, such as transactional or relationship messages, and/or messages about your account/profile. In order to cancel your account/ profile, please email [support@refinery29.com](mailto:support@refinery29.com).

Some of the network advertisers, ad agencies and other vendors we work with to serve ads on third party websites and across the internet, or analytics providers which provide us with information regarding use of the Website and effectiveness of our ads may be members of the Network Advertising Initiatives or the Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To opt-out from receiving interest-based advertising from some or all of the participating companies, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. To opt-out of participating in Google Analytics data follow the instructions: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. Please note opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will still receive other types of online advertising from participating companies and any type of advertising from non-participating companies, and the web sites you visit may still collect information for other purposes

### Third-Party Email Promotions

Occasionally, you may receive from us emails that may contain advertising or other content that was sponsored by third party retailers or businesses. These emails are not necessarily reflective of the opinions of our editorial staff. They are content paid for by our sponsors, and allow us to provide you with the free content we believe you will enjoy.

### Links to Other Sites

As a curator of information, Refinery29 often links out to other sites. We are not responsible for any content that appears on these sites, nor do we endorse them.Third parties may display advertisements on the Service and on such web sites. These advertisements may contain cookies, web beacons and other similar technologies. These third parties may collect information or insert cookies or similar technologies without our knowledge. For questions about these sites, please consult their individual privacy policies. Refinery29 is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by any third party.

### Security

All of the information described above is recorded on restricted database servers.We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We also require you to enter a password to access your registration information and manage your settings. Please do not disclose your password to unauthorized people. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of your information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Notice to Non-U.S. Users/Consent to Jurisdiction

If you are located outside of the United States, please note that the information you provide to us will be transferred to and processed in the United States, where laws regarding processing of personally identifiable information may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By using this Website, you acknowledge that your have read this privacy policy, understand it, agree to its terms and consent to the transfer and processing of such information outside your resident jurisdiction. You also consent to the adjudication of any disputes arising in connection with this Website in the federal and state courts of, and in accordance with the laws of, the state of New York.

### Modifications

Refinery29 may make changes to this privacy policy at any time. If and when we do, we will inform you by posting the revised privacy policy on this Website without other notice to you. You are responsible for periodically visiting our Website and this privacy policy to check for any changes. Continued use of our Website, following our posting of the revised privacy policy, will indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by them.

### Contact Us

If you have questions about this privacy policy, or about the Website, please contact us at [privacy@refinery29.com](mailto:privacy@refinery29.com) or review our About page available at <http://www.corporate.r29.com/>.
